In this lesson, I want to talk with you about data use and privacy.
How could storage use the data?
You can find this link in the resources, if you follow you to a sort of documentation.
There is how your data is handled based on the privacy setting you choose in could storage.
So there is privacy settings in could storage application and the pattern need, you might
share a data or not. Let's show you how to find this settings. If you open the
cursor, you can navigate to the cursor settings and cursor settings right here and then
in a storage type privacy and you will find the privacy mode. It is placed at the bottom.
You have two options. If you have an older version of cursor and you not upgraded it
before, like, the edit feature of privacy mode, you might have the start option, the privacy
mode, like the same. I will explain you the every option right here.
So the first option, if you use the privacy mode, then you see that zero data retention
will be enabled for our models providers, cursor may of course store some code data to provide
extra features, but none of your code will ever be training on us or any sort problem.
It means that if you use the privacy mode, this mode, you see your data will not be
trained or used to improve the product. This is more I recommend you to use.
As another mode is if you decide to share your data, you choose the privacy mode of, it's
the mode of share data, then they will collect some telemetry, some usage data and code
based data. It even include prompts, editor actions, code snippets, files in the repository
and edit made to the code. They also will use this data to evaluate and improve as your
AI features. Also you can read about some onboarding, if you completed how your data will
be used in this case, and there is a start mode privacy mode legacy. You see I don't have
this mode, because if you have an older version and you never choose this mode, never
switched, by default you will have the privacy mode legacy and your data won't be used
for any training and you won't share your data, but if you switch to any of this mode,
then the privacy mode legacy will disappear and it's kind of equivalent of privacy mode,
so you can still use it. There are some other modes, even if you use a APEC and your
requests will still go through the backend of the core store team, because they need to build
some prompts, so you need to understand if you make prompts, you still send some data to
the backend, they process it, but they don't store it. If you choose to index your database,
or sort of your output, your code base and small chunks and small parts, to see a service
to do some computing, and also they can might store some metadata about the code base, some
hashes, file names, also they temporary cache file contents on their servers to reduce
latency and network usage, just to handle your request faster, but all the files uncrypted,
and for example, OSH, all cached files, temporary and network permanently stored and never use
a training data when privacy mode is enabled, so everything you just need to enable your
privacy mode and then your data won't be stored or sort of won't be trained on your
data. I hope this lesson was useful for you and see you in the next lessons.